There's one industry that has quietly created more
billionaires than tech, crypto, or even real estate.
An industry that built dynasties, powered entire
nations, and still fuels untouchable wealth today.
That industry is oil and gas.
And today, we're going straight to the source.
I'm headed out to the literal Texas oil field to meet
with one of the biggest oil moguls in the entire world.
And his name, it's Brent Franklin.
And he's been drilling oil wells all over the
nation while making hundreds of millions of dollars doing so.
We're going to be walking his
rigs, hear how he built his empire,
and how oil and gas continues to
mint millionaires and billionaires even in today's world.
So this video is about to
be insane from start to finish.
So stay tuned until the end.
With that being said, let's
get this video on the way.
Alright you guys, so we just got to
the oil rig out here in El Campo, Texas.
Yes, we are in the middle of nowhere.
But yes, this business.
These oil rigs have made more millionaires and
billionaires than just about any industry in the world.
So I'm going to be interviewing one of the biggest oil moguls
in not just Texas, but in the entire United States, you guys.
So let's go meet up with Brent right now and go
figure out how the hell he even got into this business.
Why this business makes people so rich and how you can
start investing your money and making it work for you in oil.
I never in my life thought that I would
ever be at a damn oil rig right now.
But I got to learn about this
business myself because the returns in oil.
And I've heard it could be more
than real estate, more than the stock market.
So this is going to be a
masterclass on all things oil and gas.
You guys come on.
There he is.
What's going on, brother?
How's it going?
James.
Brent Franklin.
How are you?
Good, man.
It's good to meet you.
Good to meet you as well.
So you own this right here.
I do.
How the hell did you
even get into oil and gas?
Man, it was crazy.
I was mowing grass right after
I got out of the Navy.
And you know, I got a phone
call from a buddy out in Midland, Odessa.
He's like, hey, man, I got
you a job on an oil rig.
I packed my shit and I
rolled out and got on a rig.
And a couple of years
later, ended up buying a couple.
And you know, now we own
oil and gas business and investment companies.
Now for the people that don't understand how
much money that they can actually make in
oil and gas.
How much money have you made in
the last year through oil and gas?
So our company did about $40 million
last year across all of our platforms.
$40 million.
That's right.
And you don't just own the rig.
You own all aspects of it.
Yeah.
So what we do is simple.
We buy distressed off market
oil and gas investment properties.
And then we go out
there and we fix them up.
We drill wells.
We fix wells.
A lot of people in oil and gas over
leverage their properties or they don't know how to
raise money properly.
And so what we've done is we built a
fund structure that allows people to not only understand,
but invest in it without
having to become an oil company.
Now I want this video to serve as a
masterclass for everybody watching that has no idea why
people can get so rich off of oil and gas.
Can you give us the
blueprint today on how that's possible?
Yeah.
So a lot of people talk about getting
rich off oil and gas and oil field money.
One of my favorite sayings is if you want
to make a small fortune in oil and gas, start
with a large fortune.
It takes a lot of loss, a
lot of headaches in oil and gas.
And it's not just a get rich quick deal.
You have to be consistent.
You have to diversify and you got to
have a risk tolerance, but we're going to dive
in all that today.
And can we actually go up on
the rig as well and check it out?
You want to go up on the rig?
Is that cool?
All right.
Sound of love man.
Before that, is this the office right here?
Yeah.
Let's take a look.
Let's go check it out.
Yeah.
So right here is the camp house for our pusher.
What's going on?
Cameron is our tool pusher.
What he does is he turns around and
he makes sure that the rig is running.
It's a 24 seven operation.
Yeah.
It's a 24 seven operation when we start drilling.
So you've got to have a
team when you're in this business.
Oh man.
You have to have an army.
You have to have people that
know what they're doing that are experienced.
Safety is absolutely super important.
You know, people see oil rigs and oil
wells and they just think, you know, black gold
and money.
But in reality, this is the
most dangerous job in the world.
Is it too late to get into oil and gas?
Right now is the actual perfect time.
You know, what's a different market today?
There's a lot of people that have invested in
oil and gas the same way and it's not turned
out good for them.
Today's market, there's a lack of capital.
There's not as many of these conventional rigs.
People call this old school drilling.
That there used to be.
And it's a dying breed.
You know, we're going to use oil and gas forever.
Natural gas is the cleanest burning fossil fuel
and people don't realize how to get in.
They like the concept of oil and gas,
but they don't know entry points and people can't
invest in things that they don't understand.
So me coming in as an investor, learning the
hard way and taking a ton of losses, getting
taken advantage of by scrupulous oil
companies, being promised the dream by promoters.
I said, you know what?
Money doesn't come from chasing money.
Money comes from chasing problems and
monetizing the solution to those problems.
So what I did is.
I took every problem that I had
as an investor in the oil field.
I put my pen to the pad and I really
wrote out a good plan that works because why do
people invest in oil and gas?
You see it on the ads, right?
Tax benefits.
Oil and gas is one of the only
industries where you can actually write off your investments
against your active income when
the deals are structured properly.
In addition to that, I don't see any
of these multifamily deals or real estate deals that
people are doing.
They can actually get you 100% return of
your investment in less than a year when structured
properly.
So what's going on right here?
What's going on?
Okay.
So we're going to talk about this.
It's called a PaceOn system and up on
our rig floor, we've got our drilling rig equipped
with electronics that let us
know what's going into the ground.
You can imagine going back
into like the 1950s and 1960s.
They didn't have anything like that.
They're just throwing chains and I
can show you some videos of it.
It was really, really unsafe.
But nowadays technology, we're watching everything.
So right here up at the top left, you
can see it tells us exactly our whole depth, which
is 4,599.5 feet.
It tells us exactly where our bit is
and it tells us what we're doing right now.
So right now what we're doing is called tripping.
This is the process of going in or
out of the hole where they're taking pipe joints
and connecting them together.
And we're about to actually go up on the
rig floor and I'll show you all about tripping
in a second.
It also has logs on here.
It tells us, you know, if we're going to
hit any type of gas, what type of formations we're
drilling in, whether it's rock, sand, shell.
And so this is a really, really crucial piece
for Cameron to be able to sit here and understand
what's going on on the rig floor at all times.
Because if you just look out there right
now, you can't really tell what's going on.
So this is kind of like our
electronic eyes and ears on the floor.
I got a bunch of questions for you, but
before we get back into the interview, could we actually
go check out and see the full
operations on what's going on out there?
Oh yeah.
Let's rock and roll.
Let's go.
Let's go check it out.
Save you first, bro.
I got to get this off first.
That's right.
So a few things before
we go up on the rig.
Number one is typically you would wear FRC.
These are fire retarded clothing.
This is in case of any type
of burns or heat comes to you.
In oil and gas, everything is heavy.
So there's a lot of sharp objects.
There's a lot of heavy objects
and there's a lot of moving parts.
Right now we're going up on a live drilling rig.
Okay.
So I want to let people know that right now
we're on a well site that has no H2S gas.
Typically we'd wear a monitor called an
H2S monitor, which is always best practice to
have.
But because this well is plugged off at the
bottom and we have all of the well bore basically
sealed off, we know that there's no H2S present.
Typically I'd have you wear this, but today I'm
going to just let you go up here and take
a look at it.
So we are doing this safely
and let's go take a look.
Guys, this video has been insane so far.
We're about to get right back to it, but
I need to let you guys know something real quick.
Look, 99% of people will never in their entire life.
Get the chance to meet with and learn from
an oil mogul, a billionaire or any ultra successful
entrepreneur and ask them questions directly.
But over the last year, guys, I
built the number one most powerful entrepreneur network
in private community for business owners
and entrepreneurs in the entire world.
And it's called the school of mentors.
Every single week, guys, I bring in the
millionaires and billionaires I interview on this channel
and they mentor our members live.
When you join, you literally get one on
one advice and direct mentorship from the most
successful business owners in the entire world.
You will collapse years of trial and
error into just weeks because you're learning from
the most successful people on the planet.
This is the closest thing that you will
ever have to having a billionaire in your corner
and multimillionaires give you advice every single week.
So if you want to join, listen, all you have
to do is go down and click the link at the
description of this video to join the number
one community for business owners in the entire
world.
So I can't wait to see you on the inside.
With that being said, let's get back to the video.
I'm a new person right now, but I think it's
time to go out to the room and see what's
going on.
Right now.
All right, man, be careful.
Hey, by the way, everything's dirty.
Okay, so don't touch nothing.
I got you.
Before we head on out there, what exactly is this?
So you know, a lot of
people say, Hey, I got oil rig.
I got oil.
Well, a lot of people don't know
the difference between a rig and a well.
This is a drilling rig.
Okay, back behind me over here.
These are oil wells.
So a lot of people you've heard
him say, Oh, my auntie's got oil rigs.
She probably has oil wells
that are drilled by oil rigs.
So today we're out here.
This is our 850 horsepower.
Okay.
This is our top drive drilling rig.
Let's go check it out.
Let's go.
How much does this thing make a day?
So we charge our customers $15,500 a day
every single day that we operate this drilling rig.
So now we're inside of the doghouse.
This is our main control area.
Once again, this has computers where we can monitor.
We've got the driller standing outside here.
So this is where you know, this is
where the magic happens whenever it comes to drilling.
Did you have a mentor to get into this business?
Whenever I first got into oil and gas,
I was actually out on a drilling rig.
Like this.
I had applied for a job out in Midland, Odessa.
I didn't really know anything about oil and gas.
I just knew how to
move your ass hand, you know?
And so I didn't really
know exactly what I was doing.
I was just on the equipment and
I actually started getting into the investing period
about 2016, 2017.
How much money does somebody need
to start investing into oil and gas?
So oil and gas investments are typically
structured only where accredited investors can participate.
There's a lot of oil and gas
companies that structure their investments wrong and they
try to sell you a piece of a lease
as real estate, but us securities law states that
you can't invest in oil and
gas unless you're a licensed investor.
So you can't invest in oil
and gas unless you're a licensed investor.
But the first step is that somebody needs
to be an accredited investor and have a substantial
amount of capital and be able to bear
total loss before ever getting in the industry,
regardless of how it's structured.
So $100,000 is a great investment.
You need to go out and do that.
spot to start and my deal is is i
never recommend putting your whole hundred thousand dollars in one
well in one new drill or in any single company
due to the fact is there is a lot of volatility
in here with that being said there's not a way
to mitigate risk i believe that there's a way to
mitigate loss whenever it comes to oil and gas as
an investor what do investors ask for they say hey
how do i get return of investment right you can
put 100 grand in a well and it doesn't work out
for whatever reason you hate the company oh
they were terrible they lost my money tax deductions
tax deductions that doesn't typically get people to
where they need to be in investments how were
the returns on oil and gas compared to let's
say the stock market compared to real estate which one
in your opinion has the most favorable returns for
investors well i'm not in the oil and gas business
for my health right so i've been doing real
estate for over 10 years i started out wholesaling fixing
up properties and flipping them and i created a lot
of income for myself the problem was is i had
huge capital gains huge tax liabilities and the
depreciation didn't offset what i had coming in
i love real estate real estate will always be
one of my babies i like it for long-term
approaches and i love it for long-term properties i like
it for long-term approaches and i like it for long-term
properties and i like it for long-term properties and i
like it for long-term properties and i like it for long-term
appreciations stock market that gets everybody's
little gambling itch aside right doesn't really
matter what stock you pick the people in the stock
market are trying to buy in low capitalize on it
and exit at the right time and i see
people riding waves because they're not professional investors i
think that every market has a spot for good
smart sophisticated investors i think that you got to be
diversified across everything you just have to know how
to play the game and if you don't you
got to partner with somebody that does and that's
exactly why we created rise capital let's go check
out over here let's do it man all right
so first things first you want some roughneck starbucks for
him no you want to take a shot i'm all good
all right let's go check out the rig floor check it
out so what is this right here and break it
down for everybody yeah so right now we're on the rig
floor and this is a top drive drilling rig there's
two types of drilling rigs that we work with one
is called a kelly rig the other one is
called a top drive how expensive is this equipment well
it depends if you buy a brand new this
rig right here it costs about 6.5 million dollars
did you drop that on that oh no bro so what we
were able to do is we were able to find a seller
who had a couple issues with their business and
we actually bought this from a company that bought it
from a bankruptcy so we paid about 15 cents on
the dollar for the rig we inherited all the contracts
and we picked it up for dirt cheap
so you're always looking for opportunities absolutely money
is saved by purchasing assets that are undervalued and
usually from people that are in a bind because
they probably bought that for way more money than
you ended up buying it off yeah i believe they
paid over five million dollars for this piece
of equipment now you mentioned that you charge your
i guess customers 14 000 a day for here who
are you selling to is it gas stations like what what
types of companies are you selling your oil to so
a lot of people have the misconception on oil and
gas that you just make gasoline and you're just
selling gas to people who are selling oil to people
who are sponsored they definitely do this business they
only sell gas to people all the time and the
claim is that honestly Cu this기자 is a bogus
and they're aoous so i really don't want you to
own fuel and gas from us you can
don't see throughout the country so we're really worried
all of us are sort of ice
العاedarban thelaimedes that there's no money anyway
chicken suck on we're sold
on stephen i remember tailgating the
look and with this we're basically buying some
daily dash that people hire and then But hem
have to spend all their money and then you
buy equipment people can buy their scale and yours
right that's the interface with my company
what'sivalta理 because we 따라aw thing over here
This is companies that are actually purchasing
the product for us, using midstream companies
to get it there, and they're turning
around, they're refining it to gasoline, diesel, different
types of products.
There's three types of oil and gas.
Upstream, drilling.
That's right.
Midstream, shipping.
Downstream, produce.
Look at you.
You're a land man already.
Come on, come on.
Believe it.
There's guys that make money in oil and gas.
Some are the land man.
Are these people going door to door, and they're
finding people with a lot of acres, a lot
of land, and being like, hey, our
technology sees that you've got oil here.
Let's strike a deal.
What is it?
70-30 is the standard or something like that.
Can you kind of explain what that process is like?
Yeah.
So what happens is most people that are
in oil and gas upstream don't actually own the
property.
The people that own the surface are the
surface owners, and the people that own below the
surface are the mineral owners.
There might be one mineral owner.
There might be 1,000 mineral owners, literally.
And so what happens is when there's an area
of interest, the land man that you see on
TV is a person that goes out and is
typically finding out who owns the title and finding
that area of interest, and they're going
out and negotiating that oil and gas lease.
Now, whenever it comes to trades, this is your...
This is your oil and gas lease.
You get to pick what you want to
offer somebody just like you would in real estate.
For instance, most mineral owners are
looking for what's called a 25% royalty.
This means that when you extract oil and
gas, they're getting 25% of the gross proceeds
before the expenses.
This is your royalty interest.
It's also known as the NRI.
So if somebody tells you, hey, we got an oil
and gas lease, and it's a 20% NRI, you know
that the mineral owner is getting 20% of
the gross revenue, and then the oil company gets
that other 80%.
That other 80% is known as the work-life balance.
That's the working interest.
And this is where people go
in and they actually get to buy.
Just like a tenant in common, they're buying a
portion of the lease where they pay a portion
of the drilling, but they get a portion
of the proceeds if the well is commercially producible.
So there's a lot of people in oil and gas.
What separates you from 99% of other people?
What's big about my company that a lot
of people wish they could do that they can't
is we understand investment, but
we also understand the industry.
Most people that go out and raise money
for oil and gas, known as promoters, they're just
trying to sell somebody's opportunity and
make a big markup on it.
Right.
to get the slips going. All right, so first things
first, we're going to make sure you get some safety
gloves on. Make sure you don't hit anything
sharp, anything heavy. Everything out here is super heavy
and it can kill you. Oh man, it'll crush you
real quick. All right, so what they're doing right now
is they're coming down with the top drive. You're
going to help this hand right here. You're going
to pull these slips. Get up there, grab that slip.
It's going to pick up. Don't put your hand. Ready?
Here we go. Now you're going to get ready. Whenever
this comes up, they're going to pick it up past
the joint, past the collar. You're going to throw
the slips in there. What these slips do is it's
got teeth in there. They grab the pipe and hold
it so it doesn't go down. So we're going to pull
out two joints at a time. This is a double
rig. Get ready. There you go. Nice and heavy, ain't it?
Ready to get on them tongs? Watch
it, boy. Everything heavy, everything heavy. Watch out
for that hole. YouTubers. Are you a good salesman?
I'm a closer, baby. Million dollar closer. Give me
your best sales and negotiation advice right here. You
can make millions in sales, but you can make
billions in marketing. You can make millions in
sales, but you can make millions in marketing.
I think that marketing is the most important part
of any business. If you have the best product in
the world and nobody knows what you have,
you don't have anything. A lot of people downplay
social media marketing, especially in the oil and
gas industry because they're like 100 years old
and they've done it the same way. But
let me tell you something. Social media marketing knows
everything about you. They know where you live,
what you drive, your credit score, your race,
everything. So if you're not marketing on social
media, you're going to get left behind. And sales,
that's just part of it. If you've got a
good product that helps people, that is where it
comes from. Money doesn't come from chasing
money. Money comes from chasing problems and
monetizing the solution to people's problems.
Or providing a product or service that helps them.
You know they don't teach this in school, right?
No. So what school teaches you is to give
your money away, right? They teach you to go borrow
money, go to college, get a job, raise money,
put it in your 401k, give it to big business.
What they don't teach you is how to go
out there and solve somebody's problem and show them that
you have the solution and how to monetize that.
So why is oil and gas such a billion dollar
industry? Oil and gas is a multi-trillion
dollar industry. It's always going to be needed.
Everything that you touch today, the paint that's
in these shirts, the gas that's in your car,
everything. The phone.
The phone, man. It has lithium.
Somebody's got to get out here and do
this work and you don't see the snowflakes today,
especially in my generation, 35 years young, you
don't see them out here trying to do this.
People are lazy. They want to be
YouTube influencers, but not everybody's got what it
takes. You want to make money, you got
to get out here and bust your ass.
What's the best part of
oil to get into right now?
What I'm focused on 100% right
now is natural gas exploration and production.
So not oil?
Not oil, man. Well, oil is a pain in the ass.
You got to deal with pump jacks. You got to deal
with a lot of mechanical failures. Some of
the bigger companies, they make these big bursts of
oil.
Nobody talks about natural gas.
Well, that's exactly why you should do it. You
should always go for things that the media is not
talking about. Natural gas is the cleanest burning
fossil fuel. We have more LNG plants opening up
and the export of natural gas and liquefied natural
gas is massive right now. Anybody who is truly an
oil and gas investor will tell you they're
probably bullish on gas right now because that's where
everything's coming from. You got electricity coming
from it. You got heat coming from it.
Hell, you got all kinds of these data centers.
Let's talk about AI. And by the way, we're
mining Bitcoin off of it. We take natural gas,
run it into a generator, create electricity and have
a power to mine cryptocurrency. Did you
have anybody that doubted you in business?
Man, I've always had people that doubted me.
I think that people always doubt things, right? You
get around people. They can't see your vision.
They don't know what you're doing. They can't
understand your mind. And only thing that matters is
results. I've had to cut off so many friends.
You can have good people around you that are the
wrong people. And the faster you get rid of them,
the better. Bad relationships, people getting the
wrong girlfriend, hanging around the wrong people
that are doing the wrong things. If you want to
be successful, you have got to pay to be in the
business.
You have to be successful.